Stephen J. Gould papers M1437
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 3: Manuscripts
  - Articles, essays, and other writings by Gould
    - Tragic Optimism for a Millennial Dawning, annotated typescript (Box 481, Folder 9)
    - Wafting Beyond Westminster, annotated typescript (Box 481, Folder 10)
    - Unititled [Op. Ed], annotated typescript and correspondence (Box 481, Folder 11)
    - Advocating the Unspeakable, annotated typescript (Box 522, Folder 1)
    - Agassiz's Later, Private Thoughs on Evolution, annotated typescript (Box 522, Folder 2)
    - The Allometry of Individuality and Adaptation Across Levels of Selection: How Shal We Name and Generalize the Unit of Darwinism by Gould and Elisabeth A. Lloyd, annotated typescript and notes (Box 522, Folder 3)
    - The Allure of Equal Halves, annotated typescript (Box 522, Folder 4)
    - The Amazing Dummy, annotated typescript and correspondence (Box 522, Folder 5)
    - Apocalypse Today, annotated typescript and correspondence (Box 522, Folder 6)
    - At Last to the Stars Themselves, annotated typescript (Box 522, Folder 7)
    - Altus' Preface, annotated typescript (Box 522, Folder 8)
    - Beyond Competition, annotated typescript and correspondence (Box 522, Folder 9)
    - The Brain of Brawn, annotated typescript (Box 522, Folder 10)
    - Conceptual Index Fossils: Number Z, typescript and notes (Box 522, Folder 11)
    - Brothers Under the Hair, annotated typescript and manuscript (Box 522, Folder 12)
    - Contingency, galley (Box 522, Folder 13)
    - Cope's Rule as a Psychological Artifact, annotated typescript and notes (Box 522, Folder 14)
    - Dance, Dance, Wherever You May Be, annotated typescript and correspondence (Box 522, Folder 15)
    - Darwinian Fundamentalists, annotated typescript and notes (Box 522, Folder 16)
    - The Darwinian Right (and Wrong), annotated typescript (Box 522, Folder 17)
    - Deconstructing the by Casting a Brachiopod Mold in the Evolving Play of Knowledge, typescript and correspondence (Box 522, Folder 18)
    - Direct measurement of age in fossil: The solution to a classic problem in heterochrony by Douglas S. Jones and Gould, annotated typescript, research and notes (Box 522, Folder 19)
    - Direct Measurement of Age in Fossil: The Solution to a Classic Problem in Heterochrony by Douglas S. Jones and Gould, annotated typescript correspondence and reviews (Box 523, Folder 1)
    - Divide and Conquer, annotated typescript (Box 523, Folder 2)
    - Earth Alive, annotated galley (Box 523, Folder 3)
    - End Note on a New Beginning, annotated typescript, notes and research (Box 523, Folder 4)
    - The Evolution of Bibendum, annotated typescript and correspondence (Box 523, Folder 5)
    - The Evolutionary Definition of Selective Agency, Validation of the Theory of Hierarchical Selection, and Fallacy of the Selfish Gene, annotated page proofs and correspondence (Box 523, Folder 6)
    - The Expative Excellence of Spandrels as a Term and Prototype, typescript and correspondence (Box 523, Folder 7)
    - The Fascination of Dinosaurs, annotated typescript (Box 523, Folder 8)
    - Flexibility for the Limits, annotated typescript and correspondence (Box 523, Folder 9)
    - Gulliver's Further Travels: The Necessity and Difficulty of a Hierarchical Theory of Selection, annotated typescript and correspondence (Box 523, Folder 10)
    - In the Company of Animals, partial annotated typescript and correspondence (Box 523, Folder 11)
    - Introduction to Shells Calendar, annotated typescript (Box 523, Folder 12)
    - It Ain't Broke, typescript and manuscript (Box 523, Folder 13)
    - Keynote Address for Social Research, annotated page proofs (Box 523, Folder 14)
    - Lecture 2, annotated typescript and correspondence (Box 523, Folder 15)
    - Letter to Stephen Jay Gould to Donald Teeters: Reprinted by permission of writer and recipient, annotated typescript (Box 523, Folder 16)
    - Letter in reply to Sephardic Jew in King George's Court or The Anatomy Lesson, annotated typescript and correspondence (Box 523, Folder 17)
    - Money: The Abstract Non-Sacred Cow, annotated typescript and annotated galley (Box 523, Folder 18)
    - More Things in Heaven and Earth from In Coming to Life, typescript and correspondence (Box 523, Folder 19)
    - No Reversal of Fortune, annotated typescript (Box 523, Folder 20)
    - Of coiled oysters and big brains, annotated galley and correspondence (Box 523, Folder 21)
    - Of Mental and Visual Geometry, proof and correspondence (Box 523, Folder 22)
    - One Hundred Years from Now, annotated typescript and correspondence (Box 523, Folder 23)
    - Only Human, article and correspondence (Box 524, Folder 1)
    - Pulling Teeth, annotated typescript (Box 524, Folder 2)
    - Redrafting the Tree of Life, annotated typescript (Box 524, Folder 3)
    - Report to the Librarian, annotated typescript (Box 524, Folder 4)
    - Self-Help for a Hedgehog Stuck on a Molehill, typescript (Box 524, Folder 5)
    - Statement on Charles Marshall, annotated typescript (Box 524, Folder 6)
    - Strange Adventure, typescript, correspondence and research (Box 524, Folder 7)
    - The Substantial Ghost: Toward a General Explanation of Duchamp's Artful Wordplays, annotated typescript (Box 524, Folder 8)
    - A Tale of Two Heroes, annotated typescript (Box 524, Folder 9)
    - Technical Comment, annotated typescript (Box 524, Folder 10)
    - To Open A Millennium from Best American Essays 2002, annotated typescript and correspondence (Box 524, Folder 11)
    - The Unnatural Order of the Millennium, typescript (Box 524, Folder 12)
    - Wafting Behind Westminster, annotated typescript (Box 524, Folder 13)
    - What Price Glory?, annotated typescript and galley (Box 524, Folder 14)
    - Will the Real Human Essence Please Stand Up?, annotated typescript (Box 524, Folder 15)
    - The Yellow Leaf Road, annotated typescript (Box 524, Folder 16)
    - Untitled [ Time Magazine], galley (Box 524, Folder 17)
    - Untitled, typescript (Box 524, Folder 18)
    - Untitled, partial typescripts and galleys (Box 524, Folder 19)
    - Partial typescripts (2 folders) (Box-folder 524-20, Box-folder 524-21)
  - Book Reviews
    - New York Review of Books
      - Koestler's Solution - Review of Janus: A Summing Up, paste-ups, 1978 April (Box 506, Folder 1)
      - Heroes in Nature - Review of A Species of Eternity, annotated galley, typescript, paste-ups and correspondence, 1978 September (Box 506, Folder 2)
      - Exultation and Explanation - Review of The Kindly Fruits of the Earth, annotated typescript and galley, 1979 May (Box 506, Folder 3)
      - Darwin Vindicated! - Review of Darwin and the Mysterious Mr. X, typescript and annotated galley, 1979 August (Box 506, Folder 4)
      - Dreamer - Review of Disturbing the Universe, paste-ups, typescript and annotated galley, 1979 October (Box 506, Folder 5)
      - The Middle Way - Review of Advice to a Young Scientist, paste-ups, annotated typescript and annotated galley, 1980 January (Box 506, Folder 6)
      - In an Evolutionary Crucible - Review of Galapagos: Islands Lost in Time, paste-ups, typescript and notes, 1980 November (Box 506, Folder 7)
      - The Ghost of Protagoras - Review of The Evolution of Culture in Animals and Man, the Promising Primate, annotated typescript, annotated galley and notes, 1981 January (Box 506, Folder 8)
      - Deep Time and Ceaseless Motion - Review of Basin and Range and The Earth Generated and Anatomized, annotated typescript and annotated galley, 1981 May (Box 506, Folder 9)
      - The Quack Detector - Review of Science: Good, Bad and Bogus, annotated typescript and annotated galley, 1982 February (Box 506, Folder 10)
      - Will Man Become Obsolete - Review of The Enchanted Loom, annotated typescript and annotated galley, 1982 April (Box 506, Folder 11)
      - Utopia (Limited) - Review of The Turning Point, annotated typescript and annotated galley, 1983 March (Box 506, Folder 12)
      - Genes on the Brain - Review of Promethean Fire, annotated typescript and annotated galley, 1983 June (Box 506, Folder 13)
      - Calling Dr. Thomas - Review of The Youngest Science, annotated typescript and annotated galley, 1983 July (Box 506, Folder 14)
      - Thwarted Genius - Review of Black Apollo of Science, 1983 November (Box 506, Folder 15)
      - Triumph of a Naturalist - Review of A Feeling for the Organism, typescript, annotated galley and correspondence, 1984 March (Box 506, Folder 16)
      - Between You and Your Genes - Review of Not in Our Genes, annotated typescript and annotated galley, 1984 August (Box 506, Folder 17)
      - Mysteries of the Panda - Review of The Giant Pandas of Wolong, annotated typescript and annotated galley, 1985 August (Box 506, Folder 18)
      - A Triumph of Historical Excavation - Review of The Great Devonian Controversy, typescript and annotated galley, 1986 February (Box 506, Folder 19)
      - Cardboard Darwinism - Review of Vaulting Ambition, Myths of Gender, and Female of the Species, annotated typescript and annotated galley, 1986 September (Box 506, Folder 20)
      - Animals and Us - Review of In the Company of Animals, Adam's Task, Muir Among the Animals, and The Chimpanzees of Gombe, annotated typescript and annotated galley, 1987 June (Box 507, Folder 1)
      - Streak of Streaks - Review of Streak: Joe Dimaggio and the Summer of '41, typescript and annotated galley, 1988 August (Box 507, Folder 2)
      - Mighty Manchester - Review of Infinite in All Directions, typescript and annotated galley, 1988 October (Box 507, Folder 3)
      - Down on the Farm - Review of From Foraging to Agriculture, typescript and annotated galley, 1990 January (Box 507, Folder 4)
      - The Virtues of Nakedness - Review of Baseball:The People's Game, Men At Work, and When the Cheering Stops, annotated galley and correspondence, 1990 October (Box 507, Folder 5)
      - The Birth of the Two-Sex World - Review of Making Sex, paste-ups, 1991 June (Box 507, Folder 6)
      - Baseball Duality, annotated typescript and annotated galley, 1991 October (Box 512)
      - Confusion Over Evolution: An Exchange, partial annotated galley, 1992 November (Box 507, Folder 7)
      - Confusion Over Evolution - Review of The Ant and the Peacock, The Miner's Canary and On Methuselah's Trail, annotated galley, 1992 November (Box 541, Folder 3)
      - Dreams that Money Can Buy - Review of various books, annotated galley, 1992 November (Box 541, Folder 4)
      - Dreams that Money Can Buy - Review of various books, typescript, 1992 November (Box 507, Folder 8)
      - Baseball: Joys and Lamentations, annotated galley, 1993 November (Box 541, Folder 5)
      - So Near Yet So Far: The Neandertal Story - Review of The Neandertals and In Search of the Neanderthals, annotated typescript, annotated galley and notes, 1994 October (Box 507, Folder 9)
      - Good Sports and Bad - Review of Ball Four Plus Ball Five and Mr. October, The Reggie Jackson Story, annotated typescript, 1995 March (Box 507, Folder 10)
      - Good Sports and Bad - Bibliography, 1995 March (Box 507, Folder 11)
      - Good Sports and Bad - Review of various books, annotated galley proofs, 1995 March (Box 541, Folder 6)
      - Why Darwin? - Review of Charles Darwin: Voyaging, typescript and research notes, 1996 April (Box 507, Folder 12)
      - Why Darwin? - Review of Charles Darwin: Voyaging, typescript and galley, 1996 April (Box 541, Folder 7)
      - Evolution: The Pleasures of Pluralism, annotated galley, 1997 June (Box 507, Folder 13)
      - Evolution: The Pleasures of Pluralism, annotated galley and correspondence, 1997 June (Box 541, Folder 8)
      - Darwinian Fundamentalism, annotated typescript, 1997 June (Box 507, Folder 14)
      - Darwinian Fundamentalism, annotated galley, 1997 June (Box 541, Folder 9)
      - Pussycats and the Owl - Review of The Animal Estate, 1998 March (Box 507, Folder 15)
      - The Man Who Set the Clock Back - Review of The Map that Changed the World, 2001 October (Box 507, Folder 16)
      - Advertising (Box 507, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence (Box 507, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence (including miscellaneous edits) (Box 507, Folder 19)
      - Letter to the editor from Gould and Richard Dawkins (Box 507, Folder 20)
      - Promotional material/publicity (Box 507, Folder 21)
      - Clippings - Published reviews by Gould (entire copies of NY Review of Books) (Flat-box 517, Folders 2-3)
    - Other
      - Koestler - Midwife to a Dead Issue - Review of The Case o the Midwife Toad, typescript ( Science, 1972) (Box 508, Folder 1)
      - Darwin's, annotated typescript ( Science, 1975) (Box 508, Folder 2)
      - The Comparative Reception of Darwinism, annotated typescript ( American Scientist, 1975) (Box 508, Folder 3)
      - A Gardener Touched with Genius, annotated typescript ( New York Times, 1975) (Box 508, Folder 4)
      - Evolution and Extinction Rate Controls, typescript ( Sedimentary Geology, 1976) (Box 508, Folder 5)
      - Ancient Eugenics, annotated typescript ( Isis, 1977) (Box 508, Folder 6)
      - The Collected Papers of Charles Darwin, annotated typescript ( The Sciences, 1977) (Box 508, Folder 7)
      - Earliest Man and Environments in the Lake Rudolf Basin, typescript ( Quarterly Review of Biology, 1977) (Box 508, Folder 8)
      - Fossils and Progress, typescript ( Science, 1977) (Box 508, Folder 9)
      - Konrad Lorenz, annotated typescript ( New York Times, 1977) (Box 508, Folder 10)
      - The Life Science: Current Ideas of Biology, annotated typescript ( New York Times, 1977) (Box 508, Folder 11)
      - A Postpanglossian Vision - Review of On Human Nature, annotated typescript, notes and correspondence ( Human Nature, 1978) (Box 508, Folder 12)
      - Scale Effects in Animal Locomotion, typescript ( Quarterly Review of Biology, 1978) (Box 508, Folder 13)
      - Biokinetics and Biodynamics of Human Differentiation, typescript ( Quarterly Review of Biology, 1979) (Box 508, Folder 14)
      - Whatever Is, Is Almost Right - Review of Optimism: The Biology of Hope, galley and annotated typescript ( The Nation, 1979) (Box 508, Folder 15)
      - Charles Darwin and the Problem of Creation, typescript ( Nature, 1980) (Box 508, Folder 16)
      - Darwin Novelized - Review of The Origin: A Biological Novel of Chalres Darwin, annotated typescript ( Science, 1981) (Box 508, Folder 17)
      - Ice-Nine, Russian Style - Review of Polywater, annotated typescript and correspondence ( New York Times, 1981) (Box 508, Folder 18)
      - Science and Gender, annotated typescript ( New York Times, 1984) (Box 508, Folder 19)
      - An Improper Taxonomy of Death - Review of Extinctions, annotated typescript and galley ( Nature, 1985) (Box 508, Folder 20)
      - Racial Theories, typescript [ Nature, 1987?] (Box 508, Folder 21)
      - Archaeology & Language, typescript, manuscript and correspondence ( New York Times, 1988) (Box 508, Folder 22)
      - A Way With Words - Review of The Oxford English Dictionary, 2nd edition, annotated galley ( Nature, 1989) (Box 508, Folder 23)
      - Dead Heat; Making Peace with the Planet, typescript ( New York Times, 1990) (Box 508, Folder 24)
      - Principles of Geology ( Nature, 1991) (Box 508, Folder 25)
      - The Paradox of Genius - Review of Darwin, typescript and galley ( Nature, 1992) (Box 508, Folder 26)
      - The Correspondence of Charles Darwin, typescript (Box 508, Folder 27)
      - Cyril Burt, annotated typescript (Box 508, Folder 28)
      - Dear Lord Rothschild, typescript (Box 508, Folder 29)
      - Dictionary of Scientific Biology, typescript (Box 508, Folder 30)
      - Evolution of Living Organisms, typescript (Box 508, Folder 31)
      - Memoir of a Thinking Radish, typescript (Box 508, Folder 32)
      - Men for All Seasons - Review of Basball's Great Experiment, annotated typescript (Box 508, Folder 33)
      - Mind and Nature, annotated typescript (Box 508, Folder 34)
      - Neptune's Gift, annotated typescript (Box 508, Folder 35)
      - The New York Yankees; Joe DiMaggio, typescript (Box 508, Folder 36)
      - Pinstripe Pandemonium, typescript (Box 508, Folder 37)
      - A Poet's Darwin - Review of Darwin's Ark, typescript (Box 508, Folder 38)
      - Powers of Ten; Man on Earth; The Making of a Continent, typescript (Box 508, Folder 39)
      - Review of Adrian Desmond, Huley: Evolution's High Priest, annotated typescript (Box 508, Folder 40)
      - A Review of, typescript (Box 508, Folder 41)
      - Review of:, annotated typescript (New York Times) (Box 508, Folder 52)
      - Review of Gary Vermeij's Autobiography, annotated typescript [ Natural History Magazine?] (Box 508, Folder 42)
      - Review of Life Through the Ages by Charles R. Knight (Box 508, Folder 43)
      - The Search for Solutions, typescript (Box 508, Folder 44)
      - Simple Curiosity: Letters from George Gaylord Simpson to His Family, typescript (Box 508, Folder 45)
      - Size, Function, and Life History, typescript (Box 508, Folder 46)
      - Speaking of Apes, typescript (Box 508, Folder 47)
      - A Twice Told Tale, annotated typescript and annotated galley (Box 508, Folder 48)
      - Ty Cobb, annotated typescript (Box 508, Folder 49)
      - write on Wright, Right On! - Review of Seawall Wright and Evolutionary Biology, annotated typescript (Box 508, Folder 50)
      - The Zoology of the Voyage of H.M.S. Beagle, annotated typescript and annotated galley [ Natural History Magainze?] (Box 508, Folder 51)
  - Contributions to books (Books edited by Gould, or where Gould authored prologues, prefaces, epilogues, etc.)
    - Evolutionary Anatomy of the Primate Cerebral Cortex, galley proof (prologue by Gould) (Flat-box 514, Folder 5)
  - Unpublished Manuscripts
    - Untitled biological determinism manuscript, corresondence (Box 498, Folder 1)
    - Untitled biological determinism manuscript, index cards and partial typescript (Box 498, Folder 2)
    - Untitled biological determinism manuscript, partial typescript and notes (Box 498, Folder 3)
    - Untitled biological determinism manuscript, notes (2 folders) (Box-folder 498-4, Box-folder 498-5)
    - Untitled biological determinism manuscript, index cards (Box 498, Folder 6)
    - Untitled biological determinism manuscript, research materials (5 folders) (Box-folder 498-7, Box-folder 498-11)
    - Untitled biological determinism manuscript, research materials (6 folders) (Box-folder 499-1, Box-folder 499-6)
    - Untitled biological determinism manuscript, research materials (3 folders) (Box-folder 500-1, Box-folder 500-3)
    - Untitled biological determinism manuscript, research materials (2 folders) (Box-folder 541-1, Box-folder 541-2)
- Series 4: Subject Files
  - Subject Files: Index Cards (Carton 336)
  - Subject Files: Index Cards (Card-box 374, Card-box 375)
  - Subject Files: Index Cards (carton contains 4 card boxes) (Carton 376, Card-box 376.1-376.4)
  - Subject Files: Index Cards (carton contains 4 card boxes) (Carton 377, Card-box 377.1-377.4)
  - Subject Files: Creation/Evolution (2 folders) (Flat-box 435, Folders 1-2)
  - Subject Files: Old Brachiopod Labels [labels written on verso of Lowell Institute lecture announcement cards], Index Cards (Carton 442, Card-box 442.2)
  - Subject Files: Scopes Trial (Flat-box 435, Folder 3)
  - Subject Files: Index Cards (Carton 442, Card-box 442.1)
  - Oversize: Hyrtl Collections at the Mutter Museum (including photographs) (Flat-box 515, Folder 18)
  - Oversize: Life Magazine (Flat-box 438, Folder 1)
- Series 5: Audiovisual Materials
  - How Scientists Know About Punctuated Equilibria, nd; Video: VHS; 20 min. (Box 419, Videotape 1)
  - A Glorious Accident: Oliver Sacks, 2/1993; Video: VHS; 105 min. (Box 419, Videotape 2)
  - A Glorious Accident: Stephen Jay Gould, 2/1993; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 101 min. (Box 419, Videotape 3)
  - A Glorious Accident: Stephen Toulmin, 2/1993; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 104 min. (Box 419, Videotape 4)
  - A Glorious Accident: Freeman Dyson, 2/1993; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 107 min. (Box 419, Videotape 5)
  - A Glorious Accident: Daniel C. Dennett, 2/1993; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 102 min. (Box 419, Videotape 6)
  - A Glorious Accident: Rupert Sheldrake, 2/1993; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 100 min. (Box 419, Videotape 7)
  - A Glorious Accident: We Wonder Why We Find Us Here 1, 2/1993; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 02:51:00 (Box 419, Videotape 8)
  - A Glorious Accident: We Wonder Why We Find Us Here 2, 2/1993; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 00:47:00 (Box 419, Videotape 9)
  - Japanese Science Show on Insects, nd; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 140 min. (Box 419, Videotape 10)
  - Movie: Quest For Fire, 1981; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 120 min. (Box 419, Videotape 11)
  - Against All Odds #104: Normal Distribution, 6/1988; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 00:28:46 (Box 419, Videotape 12)
  - Jesse Gould: Violin Concert, nd; 1.0 Items; Video: VHSC; 45 min. (Box 419, Videotape 13)
  - In The Beginning: The Creationist Controversy With Randall Balmer #101, 8/1995; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 120 min. (Box 420, Videotape 1)
  - In The Beginning: The Creationist Controversy With Randall Balmer #102, 8/1995; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 120 min. (Box 420, Videotape 2)
  - CNN's Talkback Live: Stephen Jay Gould on Life on Mars, nd; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 120 min. (Box 420, Videotape 3)
  - A Conversation With Stephen Jay Gould, nd; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 30 min. (Box 420, Videotape 4)
  - The Infinite Voyage #106: The Great Dinosaur Hunt, nd; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 00:60:00 (Box 420, Videotape 5)
  - Britannica Awards: Stephen Jay Gould - American Academy of Achievement, nd; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 00:45:32 (Box 420, Videotape 6)
  - Excerpts Of Burgess Shale Program, nd; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 30 min. (Box 420, Videotape 7)
  - ABC's Nightline: Stephen Jay Gould on Cloning, nd; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 120 min. (Box 420, Videotape 8)
  - Charlie Rose: K. Sutherland / Lelyveld / Gould Obituary, 5/2002; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 160 min. (Box 420, Videotape 9)
  - AZA Honolulu Conference: Stephen Jay Gould Keynote (Two parts), 1996; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 120 min. (Box 420, Videotape 10)
  - The Christian Science Monitor: One Norway Street: Stephen Jay Gould, 2/1992; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 60 min. (Box 420, Videotape 11)
  - SCI B-16 Lecture, 5/1996; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 120 min. (Box 420, Videotape 12)
  - Stephen Jay Gould: Pattern In The History Of Life (Dub from U-matic 3/4"), 4/1985; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 67 min. (Box 420, Videotape 13)
  - Smithsonian World #503: Tales Of The Human Dawn, 3/1990; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 00:57:57 (Box 421, Videotape 1)
  - Dr. Stephen J. Gould: Fulani! #252, 2/1997; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 60 min. (Box 421, Videotape 2)
  - Into The Classroom Video: Stephen Jay Gould: Darwin's Revolution In Thought, nd; 1.0 Items; Video: Screener; VHS; 50 min. (Box 421, Videotape 3)
  - Stephen Jay Gould Lecture at Leeds University, 1992, 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 120 min. (Box 421, Videotape 4)
  - The Vice President of the United States Al Gore Adresses the 1999 AAAS Annual Meeting and Science Innovation Exposition Sunday, January 24, 1999, 1/1999; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 60 min. (Box 421, Videotape 5)
  - K & S Speakers: Charlie Varon, The Evolution Revival Meeting, nd; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 120 min. (Box 421, Videotape 6)
  - The Nature of Things With David Suzuki: The Burgess Shale: Impressions of Life, 3/1992; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 60 min. (Box 421, Videotape 7)
  - Richard Milner & Jim Moore: The Copulation Explosion: Sexual Freedom & The Pill, 1998; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 50 min. (Box 421, Videotape 8)
  - Antioch College: "Celebrating Antioch" with Stephen Jay Gould, 2/1987; 1.0 Items; Video: VHS; 45 min. (Box 421, Videotape 9)